# Marute Silpavatananun

88/103 Chuan Chuaen Watcharapol Village

Ram-intra Soi 65, Thareang, Bangkhean, Bangkok 10230 Home Phone: 02-3470191, Mobile Phone: 081-9398819

Email Address: Marute\_Sil@Yahoo.co.th

### **Summary**

More than 20-year experience in Offshore Operation Planning covering both asset planning, long-term strategic annual plan up to offshore planning, short-term tactical 7-day plan using CMMS which very is limited in Thailand for Planner who has both skills set due to organizational design of major oil company.

I am not only excellent in developing a realistic and deliverable offshore annual plan to support company business plan (production, operation and expenditures) and work-clash free & zero backlog 7-day offshore plan to increase work-face productivity but also able to optimize offshore resources e.g., crew boat, bed space, work location and logistic e.g., materials movement, crew boat route and accommodation vessel to improve performance and create value added as given later title as Area Conduction Coordinator.

I am good in both decision quality behavior with regards to making my thought visible, help to make other though visible, move to conclusion, etc. and operational excellent behavior according to involving the right person, addressing abnormal condition, etc.

## **Experience**

Jan 2020 – Apr 2020	Bechtel International, Inc.	Site Interface Coordinator
Jan 2018 - Nov 2019	RJSS Construction Ltd.	Construction Manager
Aug 2016 – Dec 2017	CK&P Electric Co., Ltd.	Project Engineer / Coordinator
Oct 2014 – Jul 2016	Chevron Thailand E&P, Ltd.	Area Construction Coordinator
Sep 2007 – Sep 2014	Chevron Thailand E&P, Ltd.	Asset Planner
Apr 1999 – Aug 2007	Chevron Thailand E&P, Ltd. (BES Energy)	Offshore Maintenance Planner
Feb 1986 – Apr 1999	Various (See detail below)	Various (See detail below)

#### **Detail Work Experience**

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020 Bechtel International, Inc. - Bangkok Thailand

Position Held: Site Interface Coordinator (Thai Oil CFP Project)

Job Description:

- Review, plan, monitor, and expedite all site construction interface between PSS and owner's other contractor & Existing facilities.
- Site Tie-In management/oversight and coordinate for associated site surveying.
- Develop of risk construction interface management and corrective actions required.
- Provides Mgt. oversight to Schedules in relation to External interfaces.
- Provides Mgt. oversight to Schedules in relation to internal interfaces.

Jan 2018 – Nov 2019 RJSS Construction Ltd. – Bangkok Thailand

Position Held: Construction Manager

Job Description:

- Manage Construction Department.
- Construction Planning and Supervision.
- Coordinates all construction work on Site with attention to implementation, conflicts, schedule and Workforce.

Projects:

1. EPS 22kV Expansion Project for PTT Global Chemical Public Company Limited Location: Map Ta Phut, Rayong, Thailand

2. Mitr Phol Sugar Corp,.Ltd. Kalasin Location: Kuchinarai, Kalasin, Thailand

3. CUP-3 STG Installation Project Location: Map Ta Phut, Rayong, Thailand

4. GC Polyols Project.

Location: Map Ta Phut, Rayong, Thailand

Aug 2016 - Dec 2017 CK&P Electric CO., Ltd. - Bangkok Thailand

Position Held: Project Engineer / Coordinator

Job Description:

- Construction Planning and Supervision.
- Coordinates all construction work on Site with attention to implementation, conflicts, schedule and Workforce.

Projects:

- WTP & WWTP Phase #1 of Nong Khae Greenfield Soy Milk Factory Project for GreenSpot Company.
- 2. New 115 kV Sattahip 1 Substation (GIS) Transmission system for EGAT.

Sep 2007 – Jul 2016 Chevron Thailand Exploration and Production, Ltd. – Bangkok Thailand

Position Held: Area Construction Coordinator (Oct 2014 – Jul 2016)

**Job Description:** 

- Construction Planning and Supervision.
- Implements, monitors and reports daily construction activities.
- Works with Construction Engineers and Offshore Construction Supervisor to review project data to enhance estimating, improving designs, constructability and resource utilization efficiency of offshore work.
- Coordinates all construction work in fields with attention to implementation, conflicts, schedule and POB.
- Reviews construction schedule, to coordinate upcoming projects with offshore teams
  for maximizing crew size and efficiency. Work with Onshore Ares Coordinator to
  ensure vessels, divers and other specialty contractors are identified for upcoming
  work. Insures contractor equipment, QA/QC and manpower tracked during
  construction.
- Ensures specifications are provided to offshore personnel as required for project execution.
- Ensures project close-out information, documentation and as-built are completed and turned over to Project Manager.
- Assists in preparation and participation of hazop/hazid, SIMOP and JSA reviews.
- Operations support.
- Works with Operations and other Facility Engineers in solving Operational problems that arise from project clashes. Acts as front line resource for troubleshooting problems and solution recommendation.
- Attends Operational meetings offshore to ensure conflicts are avoided and work is
  efficiently performed between Operations and FE. Reacts to resolve scheduling
  conflicts with other groups.
- Acts as principle offshore coordinator in all FE Shutdown execution phases.
- Coordinates the offshore commission activities between Operations and FE.
- HES and operation s Excellence.
- Takes the leadership role in safety through active participation and focal point in Behavioral Based Safety Program. Programs and frequent worksite safety observations, to instill a safe work practice to all construction crews.
- Ensures and enforces safety standards and requirement, Key role in advising and mentoring field staff on safety practices.
- Participates in and advises on the Frequent Inspection Program (FIP) for both projects and marine vessels within FE use. Review team participant for incident investigation (IIR).

Participates/endorser of Hazop/Hazid reviews, JSA and SIMOPs.

Position Held: Asset Planner (Sep 2007 – Sep 2014)

**Job Description:** 

- Deliver the activity planning process while ensuring the customers are fully engaged with the process and be aware of changes in customers' needs and look for opportunities for improvement.
- Optimize the effectiveness asset plans by pro-actively identifying clashes, threats and opportunities within asset scheduled scopes.
- Manage and facilitate meetings to review scheduling issues highlighted through the
  delivery of the asset activity planning processes delivering maximum benefit to the
  asset teams through optimizations of the offshore work scope schedule.
- Develop and present proposals for the resolution of major internal asset clashes or threats for management review and consideration.
- On an ongoing basis, identify and feedback to supervisor, opportunities within the business that may further develop and improve the effectiveness of the asset planning process flows, RACIs, procedures.

Apr 1999 - Aug 2007 B.E.S. Energy Resources Co. Ltd. - Bangkok Thailand (Offshore - GoT)

Position Held: Offshore Maintenance Planner/Expeditor

**Job Description:** 

- Coordinate and liaise with stakeholders (e.g. O&M, Asset Planners, SCM) to actively
  perform efficiency planning, scoping and scheduling performance under SERIP
  standard process elements; Work Order Prioritization (WOP), Work Order
  Management (WOM), Planning & Scheduling (P&S), Inventory Spare Parts
  Management (ISPM).
- Participate and ensure all data input to Computerized Maintenance Management System (CMMS) with accurately and perform CMMS data analysis for equipment failure and reliability incident.
- Support and ensure all offshore task input into system, conduct 7 Day plan meeting
  with stakeholders. Finding opportunities to increase efficiencies i.e. more work time,
  less travel, reduce LPO and operating cost.
- Actively support and ensure the relevant requirements of SERIP and OEP further stages are achieved.
- Ambassador of process to improve offshore plan and work efficiency.

May 1998 - Apr 1999 L' Air Liquid (Thailand) Ltd. - Bangkok Thailand (Hyco & Utility Project).

Position Held: Senior Electrical & Instrument Engineer

**Job Description:** 

- Factory Acceptance Test France, Denmark
- HYCO Plant system OJT & over view Belgium, Netherland
- Plant Construction & Commissioning.

May 1997 - Apr 1998 TPI Oil Company Limited. - Bangkok Thailand

Position Held: Praphadang Oil Terminal Manager

**Job Description:** 

- Responsibility for Depot day to day operation
- Health, Safety and Environmental of all staff and Depot/Surrounding area.

- Depot Operation Oil Receiving from Vessel, Storage and Offloading (to Truck and Vessel).
- Quality Control of oil to meet the specification.
- Daily Bulk Stock, Stock Control, Loss/Gain Control (Receiving, Storage and Offloading Plan)
- Equipment PM/CM to keep equipments in good Reliability & Efficiency.
- Emergency System, Metering system
- Equipment spare part inventory.
- Coordinate with Government Officer (Excise Department)
- Security system & Emergency Plan.
- Manage Sub-contractors.

Dec 1992 - Apr 1997 Fuel Pipeline Transportation Limited. - Bangkok Thailand

Position Held: Bang Pa-in Oil Terminal Manager

**Job Description:** 

- Depot construction and Commissioning, Depot Operation Oil receiving (by Pipeline),
   Storage and Offloading (to Truck and Train)
- Coordinate with Consultant and Sub Contractors.
- Health, Safety and Environmental of all staff and Depot/Surrounding area.
- Quality Control of oil to meet the specification.
- Daily Bulk Stock, Stock Control, Loss/Gain Control (Receiving, Storage and Offloading Plan)
- Equipment PM/CM to keep equipments in good Reliability & Efficiency.
- Emergency System, Metering system
- Equipment spare part inventory.
- Coordinate with Government Officer (Excise Department)
- Security system & Emergency Plan.
- Manage Sub-contractors.

Jun 1991 - Nov 1992 CH. Karnchang Limited. - Bangkok Thailand

Position Held: Sr. Project Engineer

**Job Description:** 

- Air Condition & Power supply to Air craft (400 Hz) Project, Domestic Expansion Project
- Installation equipment and Commissioning
- Manage Project Team to finish the project as scheduled.
- Health, Safety and Environmental of all staff.
- QA/QC work to meet the specification.
- Coordinate with Consultant and Project owner.

July 1986 - May 1991 Bangkok Aviation Fuel Service Limited. (BAFS) - Bangkok Thailand

Position Held: Technical Service Engineer (Jul 1990 – May 1991)

**Job Description:** 

- Technical Advisor/Project Engineer
- Purchase Technical equipment\ Spare parts.
- Project Engineer on Operation Building Project, Main Storage Tank Expansion Project

Position Held: Control Room Operator and Depot Maintenance (Jul 1986 – Jun 1990)

#### **Job Description:**

- Operate Control Room and Equipment PM/CM
- Depot operation
- Maintenance Electrical power, Instrument and Control system for Receiving, Storage, Delivering system. Fire Fighting system, Lighting system, Electrical backup Generator system, Lightning system, Grounding system.
- Electrical Power and Control system for Main Hydrant Pump Expansion Project.
- Spare part inventory.

Feb 1986 – Jun 1986 Siam Denki Company Limited - Bangkok Thailand .

Position Held: Site Engineer (BAFS site)

Job Description: Installation Electrical Power & Instrument System and Commissioning (Depot & Apron site)

- Manage Project Team to finish the project as scheduled.
- Install Electrical power, Instrument and Control system for Receiving, Storage and Delivering Process, Fire Fighting system, Lighting system, Electrical backup Generator system, Lightning system, Grounding system.
- QA/QC work to meet the specification.
- Coordinate with Consultant and Project owner.
- Manage Sub-contractors.

**Education** Bachelor's Degree in Electrical Engineering – KMIT (Northern Bangkok Campus)

Engineer License ภฟก 6147

**Reference** Chevron Thailand Exploration and Production, Ltd.

Ausnee Likhitwonnawut Geometric Operations Manager AusneeL@chevron.com

Chamanon Jothaprasert Construction Manager CJOT@chevron.com

### **Training**

- OE Certification: Leader ship Roles & Behaviors Session CTEP
- CSOC Certification Module 1 6 CTEP
- CPDEP Concepts Module 1 3 CTEP
- Crucial Conversations PACRIM Group
- Lean Sigma Green Belt Certified. CTEP
- Supervisor Essentials Workshop CTEP
- The 7- Habits of Highly Effective People PACRIM Group.
- How to Manage Workplace Negatively Dealing with Difficult People PACRIM Group.
- Basic Project Mananment CTEP.
- Effctive Presentation kills ON POINT Group,
- Excellence in Situation Management PACRIM Group.
- Developing Emotional Intelligence APM Group.
- Influencing Other PACRIM Group
- Project Control CTEP.
- Maintenance Planner & Scheduler Training USA
- CMMS Training (JD Edwards)
- CMMS Training (MAXIMO)
- Offshore work Block B8/32 Development Project Training Program GoT

 HYCO Plant general over view and Training – France, Belgium, Netherland, Denmark.

### **Additional**

Over 30 years experiences with recent 13 years in oil and gas industry work planning including asset maintenance and brownfield project execution. Have good knowledge in oil and gas industry operation including construction and operation and maintenance with strong experience of offshore maintenance strategy including Preventive, Corrective and Predictive for cost effective maintenance and improved asset reliability and availability. Ability to use maintenance planning tools and database i.e. CMMS, MAXIMO and JD Edwards. It includes the following details

Nine (9) years as Offshore Maintenance Planner and Expeditor experiences in offshore maintenance planning for Benchamas and Tantawan Field, Chevron Thailand using "Computerized Maintenance Management System - CMMS" as a primary tool to develop the 7 day and 30 day plan including optimization of crew boat routing, number of working remote platforms and preventing of work clash with other activities thorough understanding of work process flows and relationship among production, maintenance, financial, inventory, purchasing, logistics, asset planner and other departments.

Seven (7) years as Asset Planner experiences in develop execution plan for Benchamas, Tantawan and Pailin Field providing predictability and deliverability of the projects to support the asset business plan (Gas sale nomination and oil production target).

Two (2) years experience as a coordinator for execution of offshore brownfield construction work to coordinate for engineering package, materials, fabrication, logistic throughout offshore construction and commissioning. Being the contract owner of several Services Company such as Petracarbon (Thailand) Co., Ltd., and CAE